David Supple

Palm Beach Gardens, FL 33410 | Phone: 520.260.8206 | Email: davidasupple@gmail.com/ Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidasupple/ | GitHub: https://github.com/DSupps

Professional Summary

Data Analyst previously with TwinSpires.com, North America's largest, legal online horse betting company. Collected, cleansed, rendered insights and analytical reports on day to day marketing campaigns that played a critical role in generating over \$800 million in annual transactions.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, SQL, HTML/CSS, R, JavaScript

Data Manipulation: Pandas, R, Google Colab, Excel, BeautifulSoup

Data Visualization: Matplotlib, Plotly, Tableau, BootStrap

Database: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS

Other: Flask, Git Bash, Microsoft Office Suit, Visual Studio Code, Google Analytics

Projects

The Next Hottest City | https://github.com/sjpozzuoli/Daves_Eagles/tree/main/Presentation

- Analyzed U.S. real estate data to identify cities that may experience increases in values.
- Responsible for building and training machine learning models used to predict values.
- Analysis and visualizations created using Python, R, Pandas, PostgresSQL, Tableau, JavaScript, D3, Leaflet and Matplotlib.

Mission-to-Mars | https://github.com/DSupps/Mission-to-Mars

- Gathered Mission to Mars project data from all over the web to display in one location.
- Created a script that used BeautifulSoup and Splinter to scrape and store data.
- Stored data in a MongoDB, and displayed it using a web app.
- Bootstrap components and mobile-responsiveness were added.

Mapping Earthquakes | https://github.com/DSupps/Mapping Earthquakes

- Analyzed and retrieved earthquake GeoJSON data.
- Created an insightful and interactive visualization to illustrate the relationship between location and frequency of seismic activity and tectonic plate locations around the world.
- Visualizations created using GeoJSON data, Visual Studio Code, Bootstrap, Python, JavaScript, D3, and Leaflet libraries.

Improbable Beef | https://github.com/DSupps/belly_button

- Analyzed human bacterial species data.
- Created an interactive dashboard that allows a user to filter on a test subject's demographic information and see the bacterial cultures are on their body.
- Visualization created using Visual Studio Code, Bootstrap, Python.

Experience

Isle of Capri Casino Racing Pompano Park

4/2016 - 4/2020

Mutuel Specialist

Pompano Beach, FL

Responsible for establishing and maintaining relationships with high-spending, upper echelon clientele.

- Data Analytics: Analyzed spending behaviors of top-tier clients and reviewed Average Daily Worth (ADW) & Average Daily Theoretical (ADT).
- Compliance: Ensured integrity of wagering activities.

XTeks LLC 11/2015 – 3/2016

Affiliate Account Manager

Boca Raton, FL

Consulting to Affiliate Networks, Marketing & Media Mgmt. Companies, Providing SEM services. Specializing in product segmentation and campaign development at the micro search level.

- Recruited new Affiliates
- Key Account Management
- Aligned Google Adwords paid search campaigns to integrate with SEO keyword strategy

TwinSpires.com 10/2009 - 8/2014

Digital Marketing Analyst

Mountain View, CA

Created, implemented, tracked and analyzed content that increased brand awareness and promotion engagement with players via landing pages, real-time alerts, social media content, email-blasts, and online promotions in accordance with company KPIs.

- Data Analytics: Obsessively manipulated and analyzed data sets related to promotions/player database trends and reported effectiveness to all stakeholders.
- SQL: Maintained Database Schema, tables and performed data manipulation in MySQL.
- Google Analytics: Implemented, developed and administered Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager to effectively analyze website and Marketing activities.
- Collaboration: Communicated, prioritized and influenced with cross-functional team members to execute tasks.

TwinSpires.com 8/2009 – 10/2009

Digital Marketing Coordinator

Mountain View, CA

Assisted Director of Marketing with executing tasks while overseeing all optimized dynamic and static website content. Became the "go-to" resource to ensure short-term and long-term alignment of marketing strategy, KPIs, goals, vision, and execution.

- Coordinated with all internal, external, and third-party agencies to craft effective and engaging content.
- E-Mail: Created and assisted with production of weekly e-newsletter and targeted e-mail campaigns to player database.

Education

Data Analytics Certification: Columbia University

Bachelor of Science: California State University Fullerton – Finance